Sarat Roy

in LinkedIn Profile | ✓ saratroy2000@gmail.com | ■ +44 7572 546930 | Milnathort, Scotland

Profile

A 2022 MSc graduate with considerable work experience in data engineering/science based roles. Interested in employment opportunities involving the use of data for the betterment of people and/or the environment. Highly interested in modelling/AI, data analytics, optimisation and coding.

- Technologically literate and experienced in Python, MATLAB, R and Excel.
- Self-driven, independent, able to see complex projects from concept to completion
- Focused on providing value to the customer and presenting technical results clearly

WORK EXPERIENCE

Streamba Ltd, Data Engineering Industrial Placement (via The Data Lab)

Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

Conducted highly detailed analysis of previously unexamined customer data regarding the activities of 5,100 large commercial vessels. Streamba's customers were interested in the computation and visualisation of the CO2 emissions generated from their operations; an area in which I delivered excellent results.

- Developed data cleaning algorithms (Python); produced many valuable data insights
- Company work organised using Azure DevOps Boards; presented at daily stand-up meetings

University of Stirling, Research Assistant

May 2021 - Sep 2021

- Reviewed state-of-the-art research papers on sub-Nyquist sampling (Prony's method)

Buddi Ltd, Engineering Intern

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- Produced AI classification models which can identify certain household activities via sound
- Performed the data labelling, cleaning, feature creation and model building myself in MATLAB

Moto Hospitality, Customer Service Agent

Jan 2016 - Aug 2017, summers of 2018 & 2019

- Prepared and served food as part of a team whilst learning about cash handling within Moto
- Mentored new team members in the kitchen unit; frequently involved in conflict resolution

Projects

The Mathematical Contest in Modelling (MCM) - COMAP

Link to Competition Host

A member of the only team in the UK to compete in the MCM in 2019 and 2020. Achieved the award of successful participant both times. In the 2020 MCM, my team submitted a report advising fishermen on how to adapt their businesses to maintain profits over the next 50 years due to rising ocean temperatures.

Core Skills

- Mathematics, statistics, analytics
- Problem solving and modelling
- Teamwork and communication
- Independent and organised

- Advanced computer literacy
- Microsoft Office suite and LATEX
- Python, MATLAB, R, SQL basics
- UK driving licence and own car

EDUCATION

2021 - 2022 MSc, Distinction, Mathematics & Data Science at The University of Stirling

- Modules include: Modelling in Financial and Medical Systems, Stochasic Processes and Optimisation, Machine Learning, Statistics for Data Science and Representing and Manipulating Data
- Scholarship via The Data Lab
- 2017 2021 BSc (Hons), First Class, Mathematics at The University of Stirling
- 2013 2015 MEng, Withdrew, Aeronautical Engineering at The University of Glasgow